We start the specialization with this course.
最初の専門講座のコースは
How Google does ML,
GoogleでのML実施方法です
where I introduce Machine Learning and
このコースでは機械学習と「AI first」 の意味を説明します
My colleague Josh then comes in to talk about the strategy of Machine Learning.
次に同僚のJoshが 機械学習の戦略を説明します
We end with a discussion of two link of how to do Machine Learning at
最後にお話しするのは 大規模な機械学習を実施する際に使用する
Now, if you are an engineer or a scientist,
エンジニアや科学者なら こう思うかもしれません
you're probably thinking that this is all too high level and you're ready to jump to
これは概要だから 飛ばして 次のコースに移りたい
But before you make that decision let me tell you something.
そう決める前に一言言わせてください
When we taught this set of courses to our customers,
この一連のコースを受けたお客様から
one remarked that often came back was that the model by
よくいただくコメントがあります
After they went back to work, six months later,
職場に戻り 6か月後に
the model that they went to look at the most was on the strategy of Machine Learning.
一番よく検討するのが 機械学習の戦略に関するモデルなのです
So you want to get the big picture before you delve into the technical details because
だからまず全体像を把握してから 技術的な詳細に入ってください
the big picture is very important for you to
コースの残りの部分を理解するには
be able to get by in from the rest of the organization.
全体像が非常に重要なのです
To carry out, we then move on to doing Machine Learning with TensorFlow.
計画としては その後で TensorFlowを使った機械学習に進みます
That involves two aspects.
これには2つの側面があります
One, creating a good Machine Learning dataset and two,
1つ目は優れた機械学習のデータセットを 作成すること
building your first Machine Learning model with TensorFlow.
2つ目はTensorFlowを使って最初の 機械学習モデルを構築すること
Creating a Machine Learning dataset is another of
機械学習モデルのデータセットの作成も 実践的なモデルのひとつであり
When you create a Machine Learning model and it works well
機械学習モデルを作成して テストではうまく動作しても
the reason that often come back to how you created the Machine Learning dataset.
その場合MLモデルのデータセットの 作成方法が原因かもしれません
So give yourself time to absorb the lessons and then we
だから時間をかけて 教訓から学んでください
have two courses that are about improving Machine Learning accuracy.
機械学習の精度向上について 2つのコースを用意しています
As you build your first Machine Learning model,
最初の機械学習モデルを構築すると
you will learn that there are lots of things you can do to improve that model.
モデル向上の方法が多数あることがわかります
So think of this section as filling your tool chest with a set of ideas.
このセクションはいわば アイデアが詰まった道具箱です
You'll use different ideas in different situations.
さまざまなアイデアをさまざまな状況で使います
So you'll find that knowing them will be helpful in
だからその知識があると
And as before, it's not enough to just name, check these concepts.
今までどおり名前だけでなく 概念も確認してください
You need to give yourself time to understand them.
時間をかけて理解する必要があります
And know how to implement them in code.
そしてコードで実装する方法を確認します
We then move on to a set of courses
その後のコースでは
that are about operationalizing the Machine Learning model.
機械学習モデルの運用について取り上げます
As I mentioned earlier,
先ほど触れたように
operationalizing a Machine Learning model,
機械学習モデルを運用すること
and by that I mean,
それはつまり
training it at scale in a distributed way serving out the predictions,
分散して大規模なトレーニングを行うこと 予測を行うこと
building a Machine Learning model end to end.
機械学習モデルをエンドツーエンドで 構築することです
Operationalizing a Machine Learning model can be super hard.
機械学習モデルの運用は 非常に困難なことがあります
It is a stage where most enterprise Machine Learning projects fail.
この段階でほとんどの企業の 機械学習プロジェクトが失敗します
I cannot tell you how many companies I've talked to,
これまでに数え切れないほどの企業が こう言っています
who have said their innovation teams had devised these cool ML projects,
イノベーションチームが 優れたMLプロジェクトを考案したが
but they were struggling getting the ML models into production.
MLモデルを本番に組み込むのに苦労したと
In this set of courses,
このコースでは
we will talk about how to train,
MLモデルのトレーニング、 導入、予測を本番で使える形で説明します
And finally, we delve back into Machine Learning theory.
最後に機械学習の理論の詳細に戻ります
But theory in big air quotes.
しかし ただの理論ではありません
Machine Learning theory is mostly heuristics.
機械学習の理論のほとんどは経験則です
Machine learning is an intensely heuristic discipline
機械学習は非常に多くの経験則に基づきます
and you're only as good as your bag of tools and tricks.
あなたが使えるのはツールとコツだけです
So we'll introduce a number of tools and tricks that
なのでここでは ツールとコツをいくつか紹介します
work when the inputs to your Machine Learning models are images.
これは機械学習モデルに画像を入力する際に 役立ちます
Tools and tricks that help in your processing are outputting sequences
処理で役立つツールとコツは シーケンスの出力です
and sequences in Machine Learning can be either time series data or text data.
機械学習のシーケンスは 時系列のデータかテキストデータです
And finally, we will look at several ways to build powerful recommendation systems.
最後に強力な推奨システムの 構築方法をいくつか確認します
Recommendation systems or how you build personalized algorithms.
推奨システムつまり パーソナライズされたアルゴリズム
And so it's something that most ML engineers build at some point in their careers.
これはほとんどのMLエンジニアが いつかは仕事で構築します
In fact, it might be the only ML system that many people will build.
実際 たくさんの人が構築する 唯一のMLシステムかもしれません
But in order to build powerful recommendation engines,
ただし強力な推奨エンジンの構築には
it turns out that you need to understand tools and
画像とシーケンスで使うツールとコツを
tricks that are borrowed from images and from sequences.
理解する必要があります
So that's why we're looking at them in this order and that's why we look
この順番で確認していくのは そういう理由です
at recommendation engines pretty much at the end of the specialization.
推奨エンジンをこの専門講座の ほぼ最後に取り上げるのもそれが理由です
Now, you may have encountered some of this material before,
この資料は前に見たことがあるかもしれません
especially in the first four courses.
特に最初の4つのコースで紹介しました
For example, in the courses on creating
たとえば機械学習のデータセット作成と
Machine Learning datasets and on TensorFlow basics,
TensorFlowの基礎のコースでは
some of the slides will be a repeat of server less Machine Learning with TensorFlow,
Tensorflowを使用したサーバーレス機械学習の コースと一部のスライドが重複しています
that's available on Coursera.
このコースはCourseraで提供されています
Similarly, if you encountered Google's Machine Learning crash course,
Googleの機械学習の短期集中コースを 学んだ人もいるでしょう
this is an internal Google course but
これはGoogleの社内コースですが
it has also been taught on some university campuses,
一部の大学でも教えています
you might find some of the material and feature
その場合 資料や紹介されている機能
representation and art and science of ML to be familiar.
それにMLの理論と実践を 見たことがあるかもしれません
In spite of this though,
その場合でも
the details are quite different.
詳細はかなり違います
So don't skip it completely.
だから省略しないでください
Treat these courses as a useful refresher and make
このコースで知識を洗い直し
sure that you still remember the ideas presented in those sections.
紹介される概念が身についていることを 確認してください